

Melania Elena Petcu

Software Developer

Summary

I am an experienced software developer and skilled requirements analyst, with a demonstrated history of working in information technology. My user-centered proclivity, that was highly appreciated in my role as Product Owner and customer support, led me to an active interest in UX design, which is supported by my continuously practiced problem-solving skills.

INFO

Date and place of birth

15.04.1986 Ploiești, Romania

Permit

Swiss B-Permit

Status

Married

CONTACT

Address

4058 Basel, Switzerland

Phone

0041 (0) 78 623 23 83

E-mail

melania.marcian@gmail.com

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/melania-petcu

Key Skills

> Efficiency

Filling at the same time the roles of Developer, Customer Support specialist and Product Owner, I demonstrated my competency in performance, focus, prioritization and time management.

> Empathy

As a Customer Support specialist and Product Owner, I connected with both customers and clients individually and established a cordial, trustworthy and professional relationship with each of them.

> Adaptability

As a Customer Support specialist, the issues raised by the customers were usually very different from one another and they needed specific actions into solving or answering them.

Team-player & Collaborator

As Product Owner and developer, I consistently collaborated with team leads, project managers and software engineers of auxiliary products, integrated with our own, as well as with representatives of other departments (e.g. Integration, Master data, BI) and system architects.

> Problem solver

As a developer, I performed thorough investigative and analytical work of every new request, prior to development.

As Product Owner, I gained broader strategic thinking, considering also the whole picture while working through the details.

SKILLS

Technical

Adobe XD ••000 Dreamweaver ••000 **CSS** ••000 Balsamig HTMI XMI Oracle APFX ••00 Oracle PL/SOL

Industry

Requirements Analysis

Database Design

CERTIFICATIONS

UI / UX Design Specialization

California Institute of the Arts

Oracle Database Certified Expert

Oracle

Oracle Developer Certified Associate

Oracle

Experience

07/2014 - 07/2019

Bucharest, Romania

METRO SYSTEMS Romania

Product Owner & Full Stack Developer

Responsibilities as Product Owner:

- Customer liaison and first person of contact in any of the product's international branches
- Create User Stories and acceptance criteria for Product Backlog and prioritise tasks
- Map out project dependencies to inform the necessary sequence of development
- Prepare end-user documentation/manuals, that help users interact with the product effectively
- Give user and client presentations / show and tell sessions

Responsibilities as Customer Support specialist:

- > Respond promptly to customer inquiries
- Communicate with customers through various channels
- Acknowledge and resolve customer complaints

Responsibilities as Full Stack Oracle Developer:

- Development of web based applications in APEX framework
- Development of PL/SQL stored procedures in Oracle Database

07/2012 - 07/2014

Bucharest, Romania

IBM Romania

Oracle PL/SQL Developer

Responsibilities:

Development of PL/SQL stored procedures in Oracle database 06/2007 - 07/2012

Bucharest, Romania

Kepler-Rominfo

Requirements Analyst & Oracle PL/SQL

Developer

Responsibilities as Requirements Analyst:

Gather requirements from clients and validate them by cross-reference

Document requirements by creating functional and technical specifications that are used further for development

Education

10/2005 - 07/2008 Bucharest, Romania Academy of Economic Studies

> Specialization: Informatics, Economics

Ploiesti, Romania

09/2001 - 07/2005

"Mihai Viteazul" National College

Specialization: Informatics

Knowledge and Interests

Languages Romanian (mother tongue)

English (fluent)
French (basic)

German (enrolled for A1 course in Basel)

Online courses UI / UX Design

A 4-course specialization by California Institute of the Arts on Coursera.

User Experience Design Essentials

A 10.5 hours course by Daniel Scott on

Skillshare.

UX Design Fundamentals

A 12 hours course by Joe Natoli on Skillshare.

UX & Web Design Master Course: Strategy,

Design, Development

A 23.5 hours course by Joe Natoli on Udemy